<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Network Communities of the Social Sciences</title>
    <link>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Network Communities of the Social Sciences</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>hSBM Discipline Network</title>
      <link>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/Analysis/hsbm/hsbm_nx/hsbm_field_nx/hsbm_field_nx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/Analysis/hsbm/hsbm_nx/hsbm_field_nx/hsbm_field_nx/</guid>
      <description>hSBM Discipline Network#We plot a bipartite scientist-topic network with edge weights colored by discipline. The network is very dense and has a hairball-like structure. Though, we can identify disciplinary clusters of psychologists, economists, and sociologists close to the corresponding topic-nodes, “Psychology”, “Sociology”, and “Economics”, the rest of the topics appear to cluster randomly in the middle of the network. To thin out the hairball, we plot only edges with weights above the upper quartile, and here more clear patterns are visible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louvain Modularity</title>
      <link>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/methodology/Modularity/modularity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/methodology/Modularity/modularity/</guid>
      <description>Louvain Modularity#The Louvain algorithm partitions the network by finding the partition that optimizes modularity, defined as (Barabási eq. 9.12): \(M = \sum_{c=1}^{n_c}\left[\frac{L_c}{L}-\left(\frac{k_c}{2L}\right)^2\right]\), where \(n_c\)is the number of communities/partitions, \(L\)is the total number of links in the network, \(L_c\)is the total number of links within community \(C_c\), and \(k_c\)is the total degree of the nodes in this community (including links to nodes outside community \(C_c\)).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hSBM Community Network</title>
      <link>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/Analysis/hsbm/hsbm_nx/hsbm_com_nx/hsbm_com_nx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/Analysis/hsbm/hsbm_nx/hsbm_com_nx/hsbm_com_nx/</guid>
      <description>hSBM Community Network#We plot a bipartite scientist-topic network with edge weights colored by community. We have chosen to only visualize the upper quartile network, as the other network was too dense to analyze. By coloring scientists by community, we can confirm some of the tendencies we found in the bar plots of topical distributions across communities. As previously we prioritize to comment on the largest communities. The two communities of economists, namely Keynes-Smith-Friedman and Kahneman-Acemoglu-Mankiw appear to be closely intertwined, and it does not seem meaningful to consider the communities as clearly distinct based on their contributions to our selected topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TF and TF-IDF</title>
      <link>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/methodology/tf_idf_method/tf_idf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/methodology/tf_idf_method/tf_idf/</guid>
      <description>TF and TF-IDF#According to Wiki, there is a variaty of ways to calculate TF-IDF. We calculate TF-IDF in what appears to be the most conventional way, where the raw count, \( f_{t,d}\), of term \(t\)in document \( d\)is standardized/adjusted by the document length, \( \sum_{t&amp;#39;\in{d}}f_{t&amp;#39;,d}\), e.i. adjusted by the raw count of all the terms, \( t&amp;#39;\), in \(d\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topics within Disciplines</title>
      <link>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/Analysis/hsbm/topics_disciplines/topics_field/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/Analysis/hsbm/topics_disciplines/topics_field/</guid>
      <description>Topics within Disciplines#Below, we have plotted the distribution of the 21 topics within each of the scientific fields.
From the bar plots above, we infer that the contributions from each discipline vary dependent of the specific topic. Some topics have scientists from just one discipline as main contributors. This is especially true for the topics with titles we have named a specific discipline; Sociology, Anthropology, Economics, and Psychology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topics within Communities</title>
      <link>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/Analysis/hsbm/topics_communities/topic_com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/Analysis/hsbm/topics_communities/topic_com/</guid>
      <description>Topics within Communities#Below, we have plot the distribution of the 21 topics within each of the identified communities.
In our examination of the plots above, we mainly consider the largest communities, that we have previously described at the start of the analysis. The x-axis in the plots is sorted such that the largest communities are on the left. From the plots, we infer that the second largest community of Marx-Freud-Weber is the main contributor to the topic Philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction#This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hSBM</title>
      <link>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/methodology/hsbm_meth/hsbm_meth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/methodology/hsbm_meth/hsbm_meth/</guid>
      <description>Hierachical Stochastic Block Model#hSBM briefly explained The model is used to identify prevalent topics in a text corpora, and it relies on integration of techniques used for community detection in networks (Gerlach et al. 2018). Another option for us could have been latent Dirichlet allocation (LDA), but hSBM has proven to perform better than the more widely used LDA (ibid). Topics can be identified by the hSBM by representing the text corpora as a bipartite network in which nodes are documents and words, and the weight of the edges connecting nodes are determined by word-occurrences in each document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communities</title>
      <link>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/Analysis/nx_characteristic/community/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/Analysis/nx_characteristic/community/community/</guid>
      <description>Community Detection#We have used Louvain Partition to make communities. In the plot below, we have plotted the community size for each of the 22 detected communities. Note that this is based on the GCC;
Community Size#As expected from the initial examination of the plotted network, most of the nodes are partitioned onto 5-8 very large communities, followed by a series of remarkably smaller communities. The plot below shows the distribution of community size, where each community is named after the 3 most connected nodes in the given community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasets</title>
      <link>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/the_project/Dataset/Datasets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/the_project/Dataset/Datasets/</guid>
      <description>Data#Here we have the datasets which we have used for the project.
The Wikipedia Lists#Here we link to the five social science lists, which our project is build upon.
  Sociologists
  Psychologists
  Political Scientists
  Economists
  Anthropologists
  Here we have the different datasets which we used for the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Degree Distribution</title>
      <link>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/Analysis/nx_characteristic/basic_stats/deg_dist/deg_dist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/Analysis/nx_characteristic/basic_stats/deg_dist/deg_dist/</guid>
      <description>Degree Distribution#We present the degree distribution of the network.
Here is the in-degree distribution:
And here is the out-degree distribution:
Both the in- and out-degree distribution appear to be powerlaw distributed, meaning that the growth of the network is linearly biased by the degree distributions of the pre-existing nodes in the network. This is indicated by the presence of few very high degree nodes, while most of the nodes have a much smaller degree in comparison.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Connected Nodes</title>
      <link>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/Analysis/nx_characteristic/basic_stats/top_connected/most_connected/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/Analysis/nx_characteristic/basic_stats/top_connected/most_connected/</guid>
      <description>Most Connected Nodes#Below we plot the most connected nodes, both with regard to in- and out-degree:
Highest In-degree Nodes#Here is the 50 highest in-degree nodes:
Looking at the most connected nodes with regard to in-degree, we see many of the &amp;ldquo;founding fathers&amp;rdquo; of the social science disciplines. The most connected node is Karl Marx, the developer of the highly influential mode of state governance, &amp;ldquo;Communism&amp;rdquo;, and a central figure in both sociology and economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preprocess</title>
      <link>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/the_project/Preprocess/Preproces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esbenbl.github.io/site_host/docs/the_project/Preprocess/Preproces/</guid>
      <description>Proprocessing the data#To construct this &amp;ldquo;community&amp;rdquo; of social scientists, we found inspiration by examining the Faculty of Social Science at Copenhagen University. The Social Science faculty have five overall departments: Sociology, Psychology, Economy, Anthropology, and Political Science. For each of these five categories we have a list of scientists on wikipedia. We used these five lists of scientists to find and all the scientists in our final dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
